CURRICULUM VITAE

ALHASSAN ZAKARIA TAMALE COLLEGE OF EDUCATION P.O. BOX 1 E/R, TAMALE

Zakalhassan73@gmail.com Tel. 233(0)243887868/233(0)205168788

PERSONAL DETAILS

Surname: Alhassan Other Name: Zakaria

Date of Birth: 13th September 1973

Nationality: Ghanaian Region: Northern

CAREER OBJECTIVES

I want to work with an organization that will give opportunity for personal growth and to contribute meaningfully to achieving the organizations' objectives. I will do this by utilizing education, life experience together with enormous work experiences

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND					
Programme	Institution	Date			
Ph.D Educational Psychology on going	Ahmadu Bello University, Zaria, Nigeria	2019 to date			
Masters of Education In special Education	University of Education, Winneba				
Bachelor degree in Special Education & social studies	University of Education, Winneba	2006 to 2010			
Teacher's Certificate 'A'	University of Cape Coast (E.P Training College Bimbilla)	1995 to 2000			
G.C.E 'O' Level	Bimbilla Secondary School	1988 to 1993			
OTHER TRAINING					
Research publication workshop	University of Cape Coast	2017			
Tutor professional Development	T-TEL, Ghana	2016 to date			
Tutor Professional development	Educans foundation	2016			
	(World Teachers)				
Oil & Gas Training (Human Recourse)	National Youth Employment Programme	2012 to 2014			

Augmentative and Alternative Professional Development Retreat	Teacher College, Columbia University	2014
Unified Sports Training	Special Olympics Ghana	2014
Microsoft, Internet & computing fundamentals	Institute of Technology	2013
Mentorship	University of Education, Winneba	2013
General Orientation Coaches Training	Special Olympics Ghana	2013
Applied Behavior Analyses (ABA)	Ghana Education Service(Special Education Division)	2012
Seminar of National Literacy Acceleration programme(NALAP)	Ghana Education Service (GES) Northern Region, Tamale	2010
SMC/PTA Training 1&2	Catholic Relief Services/ QUIPS/ Ghana	2001
Assistant Examiners Training for SSCE	West Africa Examination Council	2013
~~~		
	WORK EXPERIENCE Institution	Date
Job title	Institution	Date 2016 to date
Job title Tutor (Education)	<b>Institution</b> Tamale College of Education	2016 to date
Job title	Institution	
Job title Tutor (Education) Special Education Teacher Other roles:	<b>Institution</b> Tamale College of Education	2016 to date
Job title Tutor (Education) Special Education Teacher	<b>Institution</b> Tamale College of Education	2016 to date
Job title Tutor (Education) Special Education Teacher Other roles:  ✓ Sports & Cultural Officer	<b>Institution</b> Tamale College of Education	2016 to date
Job title Tutor (Education) Special Education Teacher Other roles:  ✓ Sports & Cultural Officer ✓ P T A Secretar	<b>Institution</b> Tamale College of Education	2016 to date
Job title Tutor (Education) Special Education Teacher Other roles:  ✓ Sports & Cultural Officer ✓ P T A Secretar ✓ Special Olympics Coach	<b>Institution</b> Tamale College of Education	2016 to date

Returning Officer	Electoral Commission, Nanumba North		2009
Social Studies Master(National Service)	Yendi Senior High		2009
President, Nanumba Students Union (NASU)	University of Education, Winneba		2009
Organizer ( NASU)	National		2008
Class Teacher and a form Master	English and Arabic Junior High, Bimbilla		2005 to 2006
Religious and Moral Education Teacher	Jilo Junior High, Bimbilla		2000 to 2005
Enumerator	Ghana Statistical Service (Population and Housing services) Zabzugu/Tatale District		2000
Classroom teacher	Kworli L/Aprimary, Zabzugu/Tatale District	1998	to 2000

# RESEARCH AND PUBLICATION

<b>S/N</b> 1	Title Factors That Influence Students for Admission into Colleges of Education in Ghana: A Case Study Tamale College of Education	Journal Africa Development and Resources Research Institute(ADRRI) Journal	<b>Year</b> 2018
2	Special Education Teachers Use of Assistive Technology in Educating Student with Special Needs in Northern Region-Ghana	Africa Development and Resources Research Institute(ADRRI) Journal	2018
3	Transforming Teacher Education and Learning( T-TEL) IN Enhancing Tamale College of Education Tutors competencies	Social Science Learning Education Journal	2018
4	Students' teachers' attitude towards various methodology related courses in the Tamale College of Education, Tamale, Ghana.	Journal Vocational and technical Educators	2017

5 Challenges in implementing T-TEL funded tutor professional Development in Tamale College of Education

Journal Vocational and technical Educators 2017

### **REFEREES**

Prof. A. I. Mohammed Head of Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling Faculty of Education, Ahmadu Bello University Zaria Nigeria. Telephone: (+234)8034509231

Professor Yawo Grace Gadagbui University of Education, Winneba Department of Special Education Telephone: 0209024319/ 0242552348

Dr. Musah Sulemana Lecturer Mathematics Department School of Engineering University for Development Studies, Nyankpala Campus P. O. Box 1350, Tamale.

Email: <a href="mailto:wunichee@yahoo.com">wunichee@yahoo.com</a>
Telephone: 0244885613